# **CURRICULUMN VITAE**

P. O Box 60-40302, NDHIWA.

Mobile Phone: +254764207984/ +254717547418

**E-mail**:okothelphace@gmail.com

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

My goal in life is to apply my skills and talents to uplift humanity in any organization that will recognize and reward my humble abilities. I am extremely adaptable to many work situation, which is evident in my ability to work as an individual or as part of a team. The multiple skills I have fostered throughout my work experience are highly transferable to a variety of roles and I am willing to learn new skills and seek the opportunity to broaden my career opportunities.

# **BIO-DATA**

Name : Elphace Okoth

Gender : Male

Languages : Fluent in written and spoken English and Kiswahili

Religion : Christian

Citizenship : Kenyan

Marital Status : Married

Year of Birth : 14<sup>th</sup> Sept 1994

ID Number : 31902104

# PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

**Institution**: Meru University of Science and Technology

**Course**: Bachelor of Science in Horticulture (Agronomy)

 I graduated in Bachelor of Science in Horticulture in 2017 with (second class upper division) During my tenure at the University several things became successful under me. For
example, I was highly commended by the Academic, Research and student Affairs for my
role during University Elections and founders of Meru University Horticulture club

# EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2013 - 2017 : Rapedhi Secondary School.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E)

Grade: **B** {Plain}

2000 -2008 : Otange Primary School

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (K.C.P.E)

# **SKILLS**

- Team building and management skills
- Knowledge in banking systems ie Finacle, e -front, T24, Ecrm etc
- Adult training and Mindset Change.
- Good problem solving skills and Handling customers complaints through CRM
- Computer skills: Ms Windows, Internet, Email, Ms Office
- Agronomic skills including use of various farm inputs
- Good communication and Organizational skills
- Sales and marketing; Trade and industry knowledge

#### WORKING EXPERIENCE

Being a go-getter, I have worked commendably with several firms. Such exposers have widened and deepened my scope of world view. Below are some of the places I have worked;

# 2021 to date- Equity Group Foundation.

**Position**: Agriculture Field Officer

# Roles: -

- Conduct mobilization and Sensitization forums for farmers, Partners and Value Chain actors.
- Enroll the targeted beneficiaries into the project in accordance with the project set target and timelines
- Train the project beneficiaries in financial education, Agribusiness and Good Agricultural Practices
- Introduce the project beneficiaries to Equity Bank for them to learn and access relevant financial Services based on their financial needs.
- Visit Farmers group on regular basis to provide mentoring, coaching and track Implementation of the project intervention.
- Respond to farmer queries regarding agribusiness and financial services to enhance their knowledge in farm decision making
- Prepare weekly, monthly and quarterly status reports to Field Managers, Branch Managers and project Management as required.
- Organize, Coordinate and execute project activities as per the project work plan and targets (e. g Field days, exchange visits, value chain actor's Collaboration meetings etc)
- Represent Equity Group in the area of Agriculture to other Equity staff and local partners in the respective Branches, Counties and regions.
- Work with monitoring and evaluation Team to collect quality project data as required in the all stages of project life.

#### **2018-2020 - KCB Foundation.**

**Position**: Business Development Executive

#### Roles: -

- Holding onboarding workshops to new beneficiaries of the 2jiajiri programme
- Holding farm visits and follow-ups on beneficiary projects and report to Team leader on the progress of the crop and verification of input usage

- Preparing and coordinating frequent field activities with KCB Foundation and RTI partners to project sites.
- Provided Training to beneficiaries on marketing strategies and opening online platforms and printing billboards for their enterprises.
- Provided technical training to farmers groups on Agronomic activities and use of farm inputs such as pesticides, fungicides, seeds, fertilizers, and antibiotics.
- Liaising with agro vets to provide training for the farmers.
- Disseminating and giving information on disease & pest identification and control techniques to the beneficiaries of the 2jiajiri program for horticultural crops and also poultry stakeholders both small scale and commercial farmers to ensure appropriate agricultural yields.
- Performing trade visits, Extension education, and Advisory services to KCBF 2jiajiri farmers groups.
- Linking the beneficiary Farmers to buyers and suppliers
- Submitting reports on a monthly and quarterly basis. Submitted 24 success stories and other BDS reports to the team leader and also saving them on the shared folder.
   Reporting back to the KCB credit team at the branch level on a timely basis on-farm performance and any potential risks to target yields being achieved per out-grower.
- Developing scalable solutions to delivering training and after-sales agronomy support.
- Checking and managing beneficiary credit reports on CRB, CQ T24 systems

#### Achievements: -

- On boarded 3000 beneficiaries for business development
- Writing 2500 comprehensive business plans for loaning which Ksh 17.5 million has been disbursed to the beneficiary account. Also following up on the loan recovery process in which Ksh 12.5 Million was recovered from the beneficiary business proceeds.
- Registered 2000 business beneficiary enterprises, implement record-keeping and formalize them to bankable enterprise.

# 2016 -2017 -Keringet Foods Limited

**Intern:** Food and Economic Security Department

# Roles-

• Implementing Training Program targeting Irish potato farmers to transfer knowledge and skills in seed selection, modern Agronomic practices pest and disease control, pre and

post harvesting technologies and value addition with an objective of adding values to Irish potatoes leading to increased farmers' income.

- Ensuring farmers are organized into producer business groups.
- Organizing farmers exchange visits
- Setting up demonstration plots and performing other duties assigned.

# Achievements-

- Organized training programs to farmers groups with the partners such as Bayer crop science and Monsanto on the demonstration plots, training on crop disease and pests and the possible agrochemicals to reduce them.
- Organized farmers into 25 producer business groups each consisting of 40 members.
- Organized regular visit to the farms, providing technical and agronomic support.
- Setting up 10 demonstration plots for potatoes and vegetables which included Cauliflower and cabbage species
- Training farmers on Global GAP standards for those who were growing lettuce for export.

# 2015-2016 -KCSEED Trust Foundation Position: Extension Officer

# Roles-

- Linking Farmers to input sources and financial Institutions
- Ensuring farmers have access to check off services
- Assist farmers in farm and enterprise planning
- Link new suppliers to a transporter in each route
- Conduct farmers training

#### Achievements -

- Sale of agro vet products to farmers for check off-services
- Assisted 25 farmers to implement their business plans

• Conducted farmers training on four key areas; dairy feeds and nutrition, breeding, animal health and milk quality.

These work took me to the utmost interiors of rural areas.

# **HOBBIES**

- Farming
- Reading inspirational articles
- Traveling
- Socializing

# **REFFEREES**

1. Mr. Patrick Sigei

Farm manger KCSEED

P.O Box 118 -20131, Keringet

Email:Patrick-sigei@yahoo.com

**Tel:** 0727605570

2. Mr. Nicholas Wabwile Wechuli

Project coordinator 2jiajiri program KCB Foundation

P.O Box 10916-00100, Nairobi

Email: wechulinicol@gmail.com

**Tel:** +254723372874

3. Mr. Jacqueline Chepkoech

FASRAT Project Manager Equity Group Foundation

P.O Box 75104-00200, Nairobi

**Tel:** +254715472222